Atul Kumar

User Experience Designer

Live an appetite for visual finesse, and zeal to make experiences better. Making digital experiences, data narratives, visual story-boarding and prototyping excite me the most. Through my previous experiences I realised that I can play in the hybrid space, an infusion of design and technology.

Education

Hochschule für Technik und Wirtschaft, Berlin (Exchange Student) Communication Design, Sep 2017-Feb 2017

National Institute of Design, Bangalore M.Des in Information Design, 2015-2017

Manipal Institute of Technology, Manipal (MAHE) B.Tech in Computer Science, 2010-2014 | 8.6 CGPA

St. Michael's High School, Patna CBSE, 1998-2010 | XIIth 92%, Xth 95%

Experience

Freelance

Digital illustrations for educational game Monster Math. Branding for publishing startup Flying Penguin. Wall Graffiti for cakeshop E=MC2.

Deloitte-USI, Bangalore

Business Analyst - Cyber Security, Jul 2014-Jul 2015

General Electric, Bangalore

Software Developer Intern, Jan 2014-Jun 2014

IBM, Bangalore

Software Developer Intern, Jul 2013-Aug 2013

College Editorial Board MIT, Manipal

Creative Head of council of 40 students, 2013-2014

Key Projects

Designing for Railways Web | Revamping IRCTC website

Board Game Design | Research project on Indian intangible heritage

Data Narrative | Story of India's nuclear journey with data

Information Visualisation | Cricket WT20 trends visual analysis

Slow-Fun Design | Changing user behaviour in Berlin subway station

Good At

Adobe Photoshop
Adobe Illustrator
Sketch App
Adobe After Effects
Maxon Cinema4D
HTML/CSS
Javascript
Prototyping
Story-Boarding

Interests

User Experience
User Interface
Design Research
Information Design
Information Architecture
Data Narrative
Graphic Design

Summing it Up!



Achievements

IndiaHCI2016 (2016) | Showcase of Board Game project
ACM Digital Library (2016) | Paper publish for Board Game project
Best D'Vibes Logo (2015) | Deloitte annual festival D'Vibes
Awards | Multiple inter-college, state-level, and inter-school fine arts
and visual graphics related competitions, as well as in academics.
Best Michaelite (2010) | Awarded in school for consistent overall
performance for 12 years.

E: atul_ku@nid.edu myspace.atul@gmail.com

W: www.atulkr.com be.net/atul_kumar

P: +919742721604 +4917665650701